# CHUCK R. FIELDS

1493 N Hampton Ct • Greenfield, IN 46140

317-491-3419 • chuckrfields@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/chuckfields/ GitHub: https://chuckrfields.github.io/

# SUMMARY

I am a veteran of the information technology industry, with 10+ years experience developing & managing robust web applications as a dev team leader, full-stack engineer, relational database architect, report developer and consultant. Before that I was a marketing director helping businesses both nationally and internationally, so I understand how to apply technology to improve business.

My skill set includes back-end development (LAMP, WAMP, MERN and WISA stacks), as well as front-end development with frameworks/libraries including Bootstrap, jQuery, JavaScript and many others. I founded one of the first CRM web sites for the financial industry (recognized by American Banker), and have been in the industry ever since.

I hold a Bachelor's Degree in Communications, which helps me translate technical terms with enthusiasm while ensuring understanding. I'm also an award-winning podcast host & producer, with an audience in all 50 U.S. states and 161 countries.

# SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, .NET (C#, VB.net), SQL Server, Node.js, APIs

# STRENGTHS

I consider my greatest strength to be with data. I believe data is the starting point & foundation for developing applications and I love it! I frequently assist clients with SQL Server by structuring data tables, writing or re-writing stored procedures and functions, adding indexes and normalizing database structure to improve efficiency. My other greatest strength is communication. I believe I'm able to communicate technical terms for all levels, from user to c-level, internal teams, and lately, students!

# I/T VIDEO CLIPS

What is Agile methodology? | Benefits of Rapid Application Development (methodology) | Why Chuck loves to solve problems!

# EDUCATION

Indiana University - B.A. Communications (1991)

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Adjunct Instructor at Butler University Coding Bootcamp, Indianapolis, IN

11/2020-Present

• Teach students Full Stack Development, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, progressive web apps, agile methodology, computer science, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, and more.

#### Full Stack Engineer, SpaceTech Corporation, Indianapolis, IN

1/2006-Present

- Developed secure web application to reduce client staff time by 30% by automating processes Role: Lead developer & DB
  architect WISA stack. Language: vb.net; .NET Framework 4.7, MSSQL, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, RESTful
  API, SOAP, GIT
- Created web application, facilitating vendor data completion through secure form submission, integrated with back-end SQL Server 2016 database Role: Lead developer & DB architect WISA stack. Language: C#, MVC, .NET Framework 4.5,
   MSSQL, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, RESTful API, SOAP, GIT

- Rewrote legacy FoxPro application Role: Lead developer & DB architect WISA stack. Language: C#, .NET Framework 4.7,
   MSSQL, SSRS, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, GIT
- Created 100+ reports using SSRS for government entity, including improved speed through SQL Server normalization, eliminating cursors, etc. – WISA stack
- Created and launched several eCommerce web sites for clients built on PHP, JavaScript, MySQL LAMP/WAMP stacks
- Secured several PHP sites that had been hacked before client approached me to resolve, upgrade and maintain LAMP stack
- Implemented several CMS (Content Management Systems) for clients including DNN (with custom modules) and WordPress WAMP stack
- Created machine learning apps using Python and MongoDB, as well as single-page applications with React. MERN stack
- Converted several client methodologies from waterfall to Agile & RAD

# Payment Processing Consultant, 8583Pay, Indianapolis, IN

5/2016-Present

- Payment facilitator, payment processing specialist.
- Created & integrated eCommerce solution, saving client 25% (thousands of dollars per month) in payment fees while reducing processing time (from hours to minutes) Role: Lead developer & DB architect WISA stack. Language: C#, .NET Framework 4.5, MSSQL, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, API

#### Application Developer for C. P. Morgan, Indianapolis, IN

#### 10/2003-9/2005

- Converted company website from ASP to ASP.NET, storing and capturing user data in MSSQL database and creating user-friendly content management system with secure (SSL) login. Increased unique visitor traffic an average of 40% monthly
- Developed an innovative paperless contract VB.NET application, reducing errors and turnaround time by integrating client and sales data in MSSQL database and routing electronic contract for approval. Populated contracts using XML data and XSD schemas, and file replication. Captured hard-copy contracts as electronic files via Digital Senders and stored in SharePoint. Deployed new releases monthly to more than 30 sales offices across the U.S.
- Started as independent consultant then hired on as full-time developer

#### Web Solutions Manager for Netisun, LLC, Indianapolis, IN

1/2001-3/2002

- Launched and led web development division for the company, achieving 300% increase in web development revenue, earning "Million Dollar Award" from Indiana Information Technology Association (INITA)
- Developed and project managed more than 100 web sites with a team of 4 developers. Stacks: LAMP (with Perl), WISA
- Backend work included MSSQL database integration, cross-platform/cross-browser coding, user data capture, e-commerce applications (Able Commerce and Miva Merchant), creation of ASP content management modules, online surveys, instant graphical reporting, along with front-end web design.
- Most notable success included rapid (three-week) development of ASP e-commerce and content management for non-profit's web site, increasing client's potential to raise contributions while reducing management time.

### Web Content Manager & Developer for LUCRUM, Inc., Indianapolis, IN

2/2000-12/2000

- Project manager and lead editor for the company's content-focused eBusiness web site. Front-end work included ASP page design and weekly streaming radio program while backend work included MSSQL database.
- Increased number of opt-in registrations from 200 to 16,000 during tenure. Achieved 400% increase in number of sales leads through aggressive web-based marketing. Leads accounted directly for more than \$400,000 of annual revenue. Reduced web development costs by 70% by developing site in-house.
- Won 2<sup>nd</sup> Place for most innovative web site in INC Magazine Web Awards

#### Marketing Specialist & Webmaster for Centillion Digital Systems, Inc., Indianapolis, IN

11/1998-2/2000

- Developed and implemented three corporate ASP web sites: U.S., Sweden and Germany. Mainly front-end work, focusing on web site design. Also developed lead generation system, increasing web site leads by 40%.
- Other responsibilities included the creation of marketing brochures, flyers, and technical manuals as well as multimedia sales presentations and proposals.